Shaik Sadiq Ahmed Ejas

Sr. Engineer, Automated Test engineering II

IT Professional with **10+ years** of experience in building and managing high skilled quality engineering team. Experience in consistently delivering high quality(>95%) in large scale Enterprise SaaS products for SCM across Cloud & Mobile applications.

Work History

Sr. Engineer, Automated Test engineering II

Toyota Connected India Pvt Ltd, Chennai, IN

Oct 2020 - Present

- Created & Maintaining 200 cases smoke testing API automation suite using GoDog
- Created & Maintaining E2E test cases on Selenium WebDriver & Cucumber BDD to automate Web GUI tests

Quality Engineer III

Logistimo India Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru, IN

Nov 2014 - Sep 2020

- First Quality Engineer to join and scale it to 8 member team.
- Implemented QE strategies such as Golden data set, Peer review of automation code resulting in high quality delivery.
- Defining and executing functional & non-functional tests including performance tests using Jmeter, Security testing using Zaproxy and MobSF for android application
- Android native app testing and Appium automation to test the mobile application
- Demonstrated the ability to dockerize, set-up CI/CD pipeline infrastructure & Git.

Test Engineer

Jul 2014 - Sep 2014

Solarwinds Inc. Chennai, IN

- Creating, Executing and maintaining test Automation scripts using Selenium Webdriver with Java & TestNg.
- Functional testing Search Engine on Web & Mobile devices
- Creating & documenting test estimation, plan, cases, scenarios and execution
- Executing Test cases on Cross Browser, Cross-resolution & Cross-OS testing

Associate Dec 2010 - Jul 2014

Cognizant Technology solutions Pvt Ltd. Chennai, IN

- Creating, Executing and maintaining test Automation scripts using Selenium Web-driver with Java & TestNg.
- Functional testing Search Engine on Web & Mobile devices
- Creating & documenting test cases, test scenarios and test execution
- Executing Test cases on Cross Browser, Cross-resolution & Cross-OS testing

Personal Info

Fmail

sadiq.n11@gmail.com

Phone

+91 8105854242

City

Chennai, India

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaik-sadiq-

ahmed-e-1aa93343/

Github

https://github.com/sadigrepo

HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/Sterdy45

Technology

Java, Node.js, Go

TestNG, Protractor, Selenium,

Appium, GoDog, Cucumber

MariaDB

Docker. Jenkins. Postman. Jmeter,

MobSf, Genymotion;

Certifications

ISTQB - ISEB Certified Tester

Foundation level.

(Certification#: sr8842295)

Education

Anna University

B.Tech, Information Technology Aug 2006 - May 2010